The ribs are tied to a developmental process.
Development of the ectoderm, mesoderm, vascular anatomy,
cerebral development, segmentation, intestinal development,
cavities, heart, liver,
all this will ultimately allow the global emergence of the rib system.
And the image is what we call emergence theories.
It starts from a simple process, and ultimately, each layer allows emergence.
From a certain degree, complexity begins to
emerge.
We start to move forward. What's quite astonishing is that at some point, we cease
to absorb. The system goes back through chaos to start anew. We must allow
a system,
perhaps, to collapse to rebuild, which isn't always pleasant.
When,
in life, you've faced a lot of pressure, what is your response afterward? It's to go into
depression. People do not want to face their deep conflict.
The ribs are densifications between the segmented thoracic vessels.
It starts around the 35th day, you have the vertebral body,
and then you have the arch here, the growing rib that truly begins to elongate
and follows the developmental movement of the embryo
in its delimitation movement by your amniotic cavity.
I have this central axis, I have the vessels, and I have this whole delimitation phase.
It moves forward. Ultimately, it returns towards my navel. C
that's why
this whole process of cephalization, cardiac development, hepatic development,
delimitation
needs to occur to have a proper development. And from there, I will have vessels coming from
the aorta that grow, and between them, I will have what we
call a densification
of mesodermal tissues between the vessels. That's okay, it will
move back toward the midline; around the 45th day, there's like a fracture
in quotes
that occurs, which becomes a chondrocostal joint and it
moves toward my
midline at the level of my clavicle, which is here. I have
the two manubrial ends coming together toward the midline so that my sternal bars here,
thus mesenchymal condensations, also converge and
get centered here, first at the level
of the Louis angle
which corresponds to the mediastinum
and gradually to form
the xiphoid process that appears
after birth.
Initially, you still have almost two levels like that.
Because the cecum,
finishes its descent
after birth. It's also
like an image of a uterus.
And it occurs in the same dynamic that is here.
And it happens in the same dynamic that is there.
At the same time, I have...
This amniotic cavity that must be constructed, I have this liver,
and we see here, around my vertebra, with what we call myotomes, the
dermatomes,
we see the sclerotome appear, gradually, moving around.
And we see that it happens simultaneously with a whole delimitation process of the embryo.
I take the rib like this, or like that, because it
is connected to something.
Very interesting, sometimes you have people who come in and have received a blow. I found this
with boxers; when they take a hit, they can express it like intercostal neuralgia. If it's not broken, it’s often a problem with the rib and an underlying level that
is here.
At the same time I have this developing rib, I have this
parietal pleura following
but I also have the internal fold of the visceral pleura
at the pulmonary level. And this is what we call the endothoracic fascia. I first work on
the
mobility of the rib. At a second, slightly deeper level, I go deeper
down
into this consciousness to go in the same direction to shape the
rib and the
parietal pleura. Deep down here, I connect with the visceral pleura. You see? And the point
of meeting
between my visceral pleura and my parietal pleura
will occur at the level of the pulmonary hilum.
Releasing the ribs is releasing the lung.
It's a combination.
It's where I will project myself.
So, I position myself here.
That, I'm exaggerating, is the developmental movement of my rib.
In depth, here,
I now have both a development of my rib
that will simultaneously follow the development
of the parietal pleura
and inside
I have an encounter
between the two that will form the visceral pleura.
The point of meeting
will be found on the
pulmonary hilum, and thus by working
this pulmonary hilum, I balance
between the visceral and parietal.
Do you understand?
From there, my upper limbs will emerge.
That doesn’t prevent me from working
each rib
individually, that I can even work on a direct vertebral plan, not through
direct or indirect techniques, but to have all this rib cage free, it means
releasing lots of exchanges. It's a movement like that.
Secondly, it's a
parietal depth movement, the meeting of
the parietal and visceral and the
point of meeting, the pulmonary hilum. And there,
the outline of my upper limbs will emerge, which I will explain in detail.
It's an expansion of the pleuropulmonary sac.
You know the importance of the fourth rib on the left.
It's a very emotional place.
In fact, the ribs work with inhalation and exhalation.
And here, with these small cartilages, there's a phenomenon, very bad
news.
You go "Ah!"
There’s an emotional point with the kidney.
But at the same time, it locks you here, and very often on the left side, the rib
does not descend
leaving you in quite an important emotional story, and these
people have precordial pain
that begin to enter into anxiety phenomena, you simply had to clear this
level from the vertebral plan by bringing it back to
its inhalation, you take it
and then you bring it back so it can exhale again, you see, and there you
have all the work on the rib level
you can have it in the fascia
or in the global ribs,
but it's really an important area to address.
1, if you can do this
I turn, and it turns here
then I bring it here
and then I have the space where I can bring it back.
I bring it back where it wants to go.
We inhale,
I turn.
I change my position.
I bring it here; we exhale.
And that’s an easy way to correct it.
Then I work on the overall rib level.
And then I work at the endothoracic level.
And I will finish at the balance of the pulmonary hilum.